American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 28, 1870; 5x8; Bunsen, R. (Robert), 1811-1899
    Heidelberg, A.L.S. 1p. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 28, 1870; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Kirchhoff, G. (Gustav), 1824-1887
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 28, 1870; 11-1/4x9; Vogtlandischer Verein für Allgemeine und spezielle Naturkunde in Reichenbach.
    Reichenbach, L. 1p. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1870; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    Upsal, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Rob.Thalén. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 5, 1870; 11x8-1/2; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Japetus Steenstrup. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 13, 1870; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sandberger, Fridolin, 1826-1898
    Wurzburg, A.L.S. 1p.and end. In German. Thanks for Proceedings, but has not received diploma.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 26, 1870; 8x5; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p. Thanks for boxes of publications.
  - Letter to [J. Peter] Leslie (sic), December 1, 1870; 5 1/8" x 8"; Beadle, E. R. (Elias Root), 1812-1879
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regrets that it is impossible for him to attend A.P.S. meeting on Friday evening.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1870; 8x5; Royal Observatory, Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, A.L.S.: C.Piazzi Smyth. 1p. Thanks for the Proceedings.
  - Notice concerning special meeting, December 9, 1870; 5" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. Pr.D. Two copies. Concerning proposed removal of A.P.S. from its present location to Fairmount Park. See Pro., XI, 572-573.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 21, 1870; 5 1/8" x 6 1/8"; Condie, D. Francis (David Francis), 1796-1875
    Morton Station, Delaware County, Pa., 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Resignation from membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec., 1870; 11x8-1/2; Die Schweizerische Gesellschaft in Bern.
    Bern, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: K.Koch. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, February 7, 1871; 4 1/2" x 7 1/8"; Carey, Henry Charles, 1793-1879
    Secretary [of A.P.S., Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Agrees to prepare an obituary notice of [Stephen] Colwell. See Pro., XII, 16.
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], May 15, 1871; 7 3/4" x 10 1/4"; Barber, W.
    Mint of the United States, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. The engraver to the mint presents to the A.P.S. a medal of David Rittenhouse.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Rooms of the Amer[ican] Academy [of Arts and Sciences,], May 22, 1871; 5" x 8"; Quincy, Edmund, 1808-1877
    Boston, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether A.P.S. has Memoir of Count Rumford, which American Academy has lately published.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, July 15, 1871; 5" x 8"; Peabody Academy of Science
    Secretary of A.P.S., Salem, Mass., 2 pp. L. Wish to be constituted agents for the sale of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Sept., 1871; 6x5; American Association for the Advancement of Science
    Cambridge, Printed L.S.: Joseph Lovering. 1p. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Oct. 21, 1871; 5 3/8" x 8 3/8"; Chabas, François J.
    Charlon-sur-Saone, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings, nos. 83-85. Wishes a copy of no. 82 and a duplicate of no. 85. Forwards Melanges Egyptologiques, III ser., v. I. See Pro., XII, 193.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, October 22, 1871; 4 1/2" x 7 1/8"; Field, Henry W.
    Her Majesty's Mint, London, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Agrees to prepare an obituary notice of the late Sir John F. W. Herschel. See Pro., XII, 192.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, November 18, 1871; 5" x 8"; Leech, Harry Harewood
    New York, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to sell unpublished manuscript Fables of Thèodore Lorin to A.P.S. for $500. Replied: November 21, 1871.
  - Letter to Edw. W. Weed, December 28, 1871; 4 3/4" x 7 1/8"; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haddonfield, N.J., 3pp. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of 27th., enclosing bill from Professor [J. Peter] Lesley.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Leslie (sic), January 3, 1872; 5 1/8" x 8 1/16"; Carson, Joseph, 1808-1876
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Asks Mr. Lesley to assist Mr. Horatio Hale in consulting documents for his work on the Indian tribes.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., January 18, 1872; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Sands, B. F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1811-1883
    U. S. Naval Observatory, Washington, 3 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Asks cooperation of A.P.S. in securing appropriation by Congress for observation of transit of Venus in 1874. See Pro., XII, 322.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., January 30, 1872; 5" x 8"; Sands, B. F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1811-1883
    U. S. Naval observatory, Washington, 4 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Concerning material to be presented to Congress in re appropriation to facilitate observation of transit of Venus. See Pro., XII, 322.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, January 30, 1872; 5" x 8"; Weed, Edward H.
    New York, 1 p. A.L.S. The treasurer of the New York Lithographing, Engraving and Printing Co. acknowledges receipt of $31.23 in payment of bill against E[dward] D. Cope.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, February 28, 1872; 5" x 8"; Roberts, Solomon W. (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Agrees to prepare an obituary notice of the late Mr. Edward Miller. See Pro., XII, 359.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Feb. 29, 1872; 5" x 7 7/8"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Secretary of the A.P.S., U.S. Naval Observatory, Washington, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of memorial of the A.P.S. to Congress on the subject of the transit of Venus. Read, March 15, 1872.
  - Memorial to the senate and house of representatives of the United States, February, 1872; 8 3/8" x 13 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. Dr.D. In re transit of Venus, December, 1874. See Pro., XII, 359.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 8, 1872; 4 3/4" x 7"; Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899
    Yale College, New Haven, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses check for $20.50 to meet enclosed bill. Also photograph for the A.P.S. album. See Pro., XII, 434.
  - Letter to the Amer[ican] phil[osophical] soc[iety], March 12, 1872; 5" x 8 1/4"; Boston Public Library
    Boston, A.L.S: J[ustin] Winsor. 1p. and end. Request for missing numbers of the Transactions.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Leslie (sic), March 12, 1872; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Chandler, Charles Frederick, 1836-1925
    School of Mines, Columbia College, New York, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. The American Chemist desires to effect an exchange of publications with the A.P.S. See Pro., XII, 434.
  - Letter to J. Peter Lesley, March 13, 1872; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Hale, Charles
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Department of State, Washington, 2 pp. L.S. The assistant secretary of state inquires as to the importance of a series of Spanish historical pamphlets edited by Luis Torres de Mendoza.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 19, 1872; 10x8; Chandler, Charles Frederick, 1836-1925
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards publications of the American chemist.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Leslie (sic), March 27, 1872; 8 3/8" x 10 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Smithsonian Institution, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Smithsonian Institution sends bill for $2.10, for forwarding packages abroad for the A.P.S. FILM 235 FRAME 30
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, April 2, 1872; 8" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, Washington, 1 p. L.S. Encloses receipted bill for $2.10, covering charges for forwarding packages abroad for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, July 8, 1872; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Stubbs, Charles H.
    Wakefield, Lancaster County, Pa., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers a set of photographs of "Painted rocks" in the Susquehanna to the A.P.S. for $5.00. See Pro., XII, 514.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, November 2, 1872; 8" x 10"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Smithsonian Institution agrees to forward and distribute A.P.S. Proceedings to (foreign) members. FILM 235 FRAME 32
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February 25, 1873; 8 1/8" x 10"; Mansell, W. A., and Company
    [London], 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Requests the A.P.S. to purchase a copy of the British Musuem series of photographs. See Pro., XIII, 168.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 1, 1873; 5" x 8"; Orr, Hector
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Description of a new microscope slide devised and exhibited before the Franklin Institute by Dr. D. S. Holman. See Pro., XIII, 155.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 29, 1873; 5" x 8"; Penrose, R. A. F. (Richard Alexander Fullerton), 1827-1908
    1331 Spruce st., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Accepts appointment to prepare obituary notice of Dr. Hugh L. Hodge. See Pro., XIII, 181.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, April 15, 1873; 5 3/8" x 8 1/8"; Bradley, Frank Howe, 1838-1879
    East Tennessee University, Knoxville, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Desires to purchase a complete set of A.P.S. Proceedings. See Pro., XIII, 209.
  - Letter to the President of the Philosophical Society of Philadelphia (sic), October 24, 1873; 5" x 8 1/16"; Belcourt, George Antoine, 1803-1874
    Memramcock, New Brunswick, Canada, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Regarding plans for the publication of his Algonquin dictionary. See Pro., XIII, 266.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., November 11, 1873; 5" x 7 7/8"; Durrie, Daniel S. (Daniel Steele), 1819-1892
    Madison, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. The State Historical Society of Wisconsin offers to supply the A.P.S. with public documents of Wisconsin for the past ten years, if the same are desired. See Pro., XIII, 268.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 18, 1873; 5 1/4" x 8 3/8"; Dexter, Henry, 1806-1876
    Cambridge, Mass., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to know whether the A.P.S. would purchase a bust of Agassiz for $25. See Pro., XIV, 1.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Feb. 4, 1874; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Nystrom, John W. (John William), 1824-1885
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Requests Society's opinion of his pamphlet on dynamics. On same sheet is letter from Nystrom to A.P.S., 1874.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred the paper by Edward D. Cope, February 10, 1874; American Philosophical Society
    "Supplement to the extinct Batrachia and Reptilia of North America," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Joseph Leidy, J. S. Newberry, J. P[eter] Lesley. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to Prof. J. P[eter] Lesley, secretary of A.P.S., April 7, 1874; 6 1/2 x 4 1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Agrees to write obituary of Jos. Harrison. See Proc. Am. Phil. Soc., VOL. XIV(1876).
  - Letter to Prof. Lesley, May 1, 1874; 8x5; Blasius, William, 1818-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Desires use of Society's library for meteorological study.
  - Letter to Mr. J. P[eter] Leslie [Lesley], secretary of A.P.S., May 1, 1874; 7x4 1/2; Browne, John C. (John Coates), 1838-1918
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines membership in A.P.S.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B.Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., May 6, 1874; 10x8; Pennsylvania. Bureau of statistics of labor and agriculture
    Harrisburg, A.L.S.: Thomas J.Bigham. 2p., end. Asks A.P.S. to distribute copies of Bureau's report.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, May 30, 1874; 8x5; United States Naval Observatory.
    Washington, A.L.S.: J[oseph] E[verett] Nourse. 1p., end. Forwarding Society's Proc. to Admiral Wilkes. Offers pamphlet.(wanting).
  - Letter to Prof. J. P. Lesley, librarian of A.P.S., July 22, 1874; 9 1/2 x 6 1/2; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Offers to give A.P.S. European publications of deceased father, Louis Agassiz.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Sept. 18, 1874; Société de pharmacie de Paris
    A.L.S. 2p. In French.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Oct.1, 1874; 9x5-1/2; Kirtland, J. P. (Jared Potter), 1793-1877
    East Rockport, Ohio, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Inquires why he is receiving Proc. from Society.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Oct. 23, 1874; 10x8; Rantoul literary society
    Rantoul, Ill., A.L.S.: A.H.Bailey, President. 1p.and end. Received Society's Proc. Encloses clipping about his society's lecture course.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, Nov. 11, 1874; 10x8; United States. Bureau of Education
    Washington, L.S.: John Eaton, commissioner. 1p. Seeks statistics on Society's library for Bureau's book on U.S. libraries.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Nov. 23, 1874; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States. Dept. of the Interior
    Washington, L.S.: C[olumbus] Delano, secretary. 2p., end. In re: gives address of J.D.Cox; refers question of C.King's address to War Dept.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Nov. 25, 1874; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States. Army. Corps of Engineers
    Washington, L.S.:Tho[mas] Lincoln Casey. 1p. Address of Clarence King.
  - Letter to J.P. Leslie [sic], Dec. 9, 1874; 8x5; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Desires notices of Proc. for rcod in New York Tribune.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Dec.10, 1874; 10x8; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines to sit on committee to report on S.Meunier's Cours de Géologie Comparée Professé au Muséum d'Histoire Naturalle.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 15, 1874; 13x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: C.J.Matthes. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J. P. Lesley, Dec. 26, 1874; Rantoul literary society
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to secretary of American philosophical society [J.P.Lesley], 1874; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Nystrom, John W. (John William), 1824-1885
    Phila., Printed L.filled in in ms.S. 1p. Sends Society pamphlet on dynamics;asks opinion of it. On same sheet as letter from Nystrom to Lesley, Feb.4, 1874.
  - List of publications sent by the Cambridge museum in exchange for the Society's publications, [1874]; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.
  - Letter to [Mathew Carey Lea], Jan.6, [1875]; 7x4-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Dr.ofL. 1p. Sending R.Hare's pamphlet on blowpipe to Benjamin Silliman. On same sheet as letter from Lea to Lesley, Feb.5, 1875.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Jan. 11, 1875; 8x5; Smith, Lloyd P. (Lloyd Pearsall), 1822-1886
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Resigns membership in A.P.S.
  - Letter to [J.] Peter Lesley, Feb. 2, 1875; 9x6; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Needs two dates to complete obituary of Jos. Harrison.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Feb. 5, 1875; 7x4-1/2; Lea, M. Carey (Mathew Carey), 1823-1897
    Chelten Hills, Pa., A.L.S. 3p., end. Wishes to obtain R.Hare's pamphlet on blowpipe for B.Silliman. On same sheet is letter from [Lesley] to [Lea], Jan.6[sic], [1875].
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Feb., [1875 ?]; 8x5; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning obituary of Joseph Harrison.
  - Letter to J.P.Lesley, March 10, 1875; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asks to renew books borrowed from Society's library.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[J.Peter Lesley], March 13, 1875; 10x7-1/2; Holden, William
    Columbus, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking exchange of H. Wood and E. Cope's memoirs on Arachnida and Myriapoda for Ohio geological reports.
  - Letter to American philosophical society [Mary Lesley], March 16, 1875; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Asks to renew books borrowed from Society's library.
  - Request of... for additional appropriation to meet expense of Harrison Allen's paper, March 18, 1875; 5" x 8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S.: J[ohn] L. Leconte, Charles M. Cresson. Request "between 90 & 100 dollars."
  - Note to American philosophical society, March 22, 1875; 8x5; Waugh, Samuel Bell
    A.N.S. 1p.,end.by Mary Lesley,and 1p. memo. Asking Society to give bearer portrait of B.Franklin. Memo pertains to B.Franklin portrait by C.W.Peale. FILM54-66 FRAME167
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], March 31, 1875; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States. Bureau of Education
    Washington, L.S.: John Eato[n]. 1p., end. Mutilated. Seeks statistics about Society's library for Bureau's book about U.S. libraries.
  - Note to W[illia]m Holden, Columbus, April 24, 1875; 5x3; American Philosophical Society
    N. 1p.on postal card and add. Acknowledges receipt of letter.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], May 18, 1875; 10x7-1/2; United States. Bureau of Education
    Washington, L.S.: John Eaton. 3p.and add. Asks replies to questions about A.P.S. library for Bureau's book on U.S. libraries
  - Letter to Mary Lesley, June 18, 1875; 8x5-1/2; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to renew books borrowed from Society's library.
  - Letter to George B. Wood, June 30, 1875; 12-1/2x8; Thornton, Edward, Sir, 1817-1906
    Washington, L.S. 4p., end. Suggestions as to persons Society considers eligible for Albert medal of Society for the encouragement of arts. Encloses list of previous conferees(see in Broadside collection).
  - Letter to [Sir Edward Thornton], Sept. 12, 1875; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr. of L. 2p.and end. Suggests Joseph Henry for Albert medal of Society for the encouragement of arts, and summarizes his contributions.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Sept. 24, 1875; 8x5; Law, Edward E.
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines to prepare obituary of W.Whitman.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Oct. 9, 1875; 8x5; Hare, J. I. Clark (John Innes Clark)
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Declines to write obituary of Horace Binney; suggests G.Rosengarten to do it.
  - Extract from the will of...proved at Philadelphia, Oct. 12, 1875; 13x8; Peale, Caroline, 1798-1878
    Typed copy 1p. Concerns her bequest of Franklin Peale Stone Age collection to the A.P.S.
    Not Found: 5/2011
  - Letter to Geo[rge] B[acon] Wood, Oct. 30, 1875; 10x8; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end.: Referred...to Curators to consider and report As executor of C.E.G. Peale's will, discusses her gift of Franklin Peale collection of Stone Age implements to A.P.S.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, Nov. 9, 1875; 10x8; Masonic academy, Milton, Fla.
    Milton, Fla., L.S.: Rev.Jas.O.Andrew, president, and three others. 1p. Asks for Society's Trans. for their library.
  - Resolution of acceptance of Caroline E. G. Peale's bequest of the Franklin Peale Stone Age collection, Nov. 19, 1875; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Phila.] Draft 1p. and end. Refers to Robert Patterson as executor of will. Cf. Proceedings, v.14, p.649.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 11, 1875; 13x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
  - Letter to Dr. G.D. Brinton[sic], Dec. 29, 1875; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Valentini, Philipp J. J. (Philipp Johann Josef), 1828-1899
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Gives new address. Discusses publication of manuscript on Mexican calendar stone.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 30, 1875; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: H.Siegel. 2p. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Jan. 8, 1876; 7x4-1/2; Shea, John Gilmary, 1824-1892
    Elizabeth, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Looking for prospectus by Dom Gauthey on transmitting sound.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 17, 1876; 11x8-1/2; Germany. Resident Centennial Commission
    Phila., L.S.:John D.Lankenau. 1p., end. Asks return of C.Kesselmeyer's letter.
  - Letter to Prof.[J.P.]Lesley, Jan. 20, 1876; 8x5; Valentini, Philipp J. J. (Philipp Johann Josef), 1828-1899. Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Criticizes P.Valentini's manuscript on Mexican calendar stone.
  - Letter to Prof.[J.P.]Lesley, Jan. 20, 1876; 8x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 25, 1876; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Société de physique et d'histoire naturelle de Genève
    Geneva, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: C.Marignac. 1p. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to A.P.S., Feb. 14, 1876; 10x8; Barnwell, James G.
    Phila., L.S. 1p., end. by M[ary] L[esley]. Collecting statistics of Phila. libraries for Centennial Exhibition; needs more information about Society's library.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Feb. 15, 1876; 8x5; United States Naval Observatory
    Washington, L.S.: C[harles] H[enry] Davis. 2p. Concerning Society's promotion of Polaris expedition.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 17, 1876; 11x8-1/2; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 2p., end. Asks to borrow Eliot Indian Bible to display at Centennial Exhibition. Gives Joseph Pancoast and William Sellers as references.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 7, 1876; 11x8-1/2; Philadelphia (Pa.). Committee on Restoration of Independence Hall
    Phila., A.L.S.: Frank M[arx] Etting 2p., end. Requests loan of Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence for Centennial Exposition. End.: Referred to the Curators to report.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, March 9, 1876; 9x6; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p., end. Will be glad to speak to A.P.S. Library Committee about loan of Eliot Bible for Centennial.
  - Letter to the Smithsonian institution, March 18, 1876; 10x9; Bayerische Staatsbibliothek
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Karl Hahn. 1p. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Report on loan of Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence to the Committee on Restoration of Independence Hall, March 23, 1876; 9x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    D.S.: J[oseph] Carson, Hector Tyndale, Charles M. Cresson 2p., and end. (see APS. Curators. Reports) Curators favor loan. Draft to be exhibited in Independence Hall for duration of Centennial Year.
  - Reports, March 23, 1876 - Dec. 3, 1936; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] D. 46 items various sizes. See Table of contents in box. For later Curators' reports see A.P.S. Yearbooks.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 25, 1876; 8x5; Welsh, John, 1805-1886
    A.L.S. 1p. Approves loan of Eliot Bible to A.J. Holman & co. for display at Centennial.
  - Letter to Jos[eph] Carson, March 28, 1876; 9x6; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)